So no. This data set isn't tidy.
لذا لا. مجموعة البيانات هذه ليست مرتبة.
For tidy data, we need each variable to be a column,
للحصول على بيانات مرتبة، نحتاج أن يكون كل متغير عمودًا،
each observation to be a row,
وأن تكون كل ملاحظة صفًا،
and each type of observational unit to be a table.
وكل نوع من وحدة الملاحظات جدولًا.
So first, we have duplicate representation of data.
لذا أولًا، لدينا تمثيل مكرر لبيانات التاريخ.
One in this column here, the date column,
واحد في هذا العمود هنا، عمود التاريخ،
January 5th 2004 for example, month, day,
يناير / 5 / 2004 على سبيل المثال، شهر، يوم
year that also again at the end
سنة، ومرة أخرى في نهاية
of the data set here with Year and Month having their own columns.
مجموعة البيانات هنا، حيث السنة والشهر لديهما الأعمدة الخاصة بهما.
Here is the duplicate representation of date data.
وها هنا التمثيل المتكرر لبيانات التاريخ.
So that means we have two representations of year and month data.
وهذا يعني أن لدينا تمثيلين لبيانات السنة والشهر.
For tidy, we need one day,
لمزيد من الترتيب، نحتاج أن يكون لدينا يوم واحد،
one month and one year.
شهر واحد وسنة واحدة.
So if we have to make updates to the data we only have to do it in one place.
لذا إذا كان علينا عمل تحديثات على البيانات، فعلينا القيام بها فقط في مكان واحد.
I would also argue that there are two types of observational units in this dataset;
وسأرجح أيضًا أن هناك نوعان من وحدات الملاحظات في مجموعة البيانات هذه؛
job posting data and then company data.
بيانات طلب وظيفة وبعد ذلك بيانات الشركة.
To make this tidy, we would have to separate these into two tables: One,
لنجعلها أكتر ترتيبًا، علينا فصلها في جدولين: الأول،
the job posting data having everything in this dataset except for this AboutC column.
بيانات طلب وظيفة يحتوي على كل شيء في مجموعة البيانات ماعدا عمود AboutC هذا.
And then a second, the Company table with
وبعد ذلك الثاني، جدول الشركة
only desk company column and this AboutC column or About Company column.
الذي يحتوي فقط على عمود desk company وعمود AboutC هذا أو عمود About Company.
For this walk through though we are going to skip documenting
لذلك للحصول على هذه المعاينة سنتخطى توثيق
this lack of tidiness and not fix it in the clean step.
هذا الافتقار إلى الترتيب ولن نصلحه في خطوة المسح.
I want to keep this lesson short.
أريد أن أختصر هذا الدرس.
For one it also because non-tidy data is okay sometimes.
على سبيل المثال، لأن البيانات غير المرتبة تكون جيدة أحيانًا.
Jeff Leek explains this well in his blog post on non-tidy data.
يشرح eff Lee هذا جيدًا في مدونته عن البيانات غير المرتبة.
Pause the video and take a moment to read this paragraph.
أوقفوا مقطع الفيديو وخذوا لحظة من وقتكم لقراءة هذه الفقرة.
Take my word that forth this walkthrough and the analyses and visualizations that you are
صدقوا كلامي أن هذه المعاينة والتحليلات والمرئيات التي
going to create are data in a non tidy format works
ستقومون بإنشائها هي بيانات في أعمال ذات تنسيق غير مرتب.